A Finding Aid to the William P. Daley Papers, 1905-2016 (bulk 1951-2001), in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Reference Files, 1951-2001, undated; Series 9; Archival Resource Key; 1 Linear foot Box 13; (Box 13; 1.0 linear foot)
  - Moravian Tile Works/Henry Chapman Mercer, 1966, 1979-1991, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Native American Art, 1980, 1982, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 40-41)
  - New Clay Body, 1990-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - Pickett Collection, 1985, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - Plaster Mixing, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - Quotes and Ideas for Future Essays, 1991, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 45)
  - Raku Glazes, 1968, 1980, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 46)
  - South America, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 47)
  - Statements on Art by Artists, 1951, 1981-1991, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 48)
  - Terra Sigillata Composition, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 49)
  - Word Processors, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 50)
- Printed Material, 1936-2004, undated; Series 10; Archival Resource Key; 1.9 Linear feet Boxes 14-15
  This series houses printed material and publications including newspaper and magazine clippings on Daley, Helen Drutt Gallery, and ceramics in general. Files of clippings about Daley contain many reviews of his work. Also within this series are numerous exhibition announcements and invitations. These are arranged by medium and chronologically under each heading, with separate folders for the galleries from which Daley received a large amount of material. This series contains exhibition catalogs primarily from the National Ceramic Exhibition (later called The Ceramic National), and various copies of journals and newsletters on the topic of ceramics. Also found are manuals on ceramics, miscellaneous published essays, brochures, and art postcards.
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Architectural Ceramics, 1974-1992, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Ceramics, 1978-1999, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 2-9)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Fiber, 1962, 1978-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Glass, 1979-1998, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Metal, 1985-1998, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Painting, 1973-1999, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 13-15)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Printmaking, 1983-1997, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Wood, 1979-1998, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Braunstein/Quay Gallery, 1980-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 18-19)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Exhibit A, 1973-1984, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 20-21)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Garth Clark Gallery, 1981-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 22-27)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Helen Drutt Gallery, 1974-1998, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 28-31)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Miscellaneous, 1981-1998, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Clippings, William Daley, 1951-1976, 1979-1998, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
  - Clippings, Helen Drutt Gallery, 1975-1990, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, Ceramics, 1938, 1940, 1966-1995, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, National Ceramic Exhibition, 1936, 1937, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, National Ceramic Exhibition, 1940, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, The Ceramic National, 1958-1959, 1962-1966, 1968-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 7-8)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Miscellaneous, 1957-1970, 1983-1997, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 9-10)
  - American Craft Museum News, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Arts & Crafts, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Ceramic Arts Newsletter, 1983-1984, 1986, 1988-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 13-14)
  - Ceramic Arts Notes, 1993, 1994, 1996, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Ceramic Industry, 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Ceramics Monthly, 1954-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Ceramophile, 2000-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Clay Talks: Reflections by American Master Ceramicists, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Craft Horizons, 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - NCECA Newsletter, 1980-1981, 1985, 1991-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - The Shards Newsletter, 1980-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous Newsletters and Journals, 1959, 1980-2001, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Manuals, Glazes by Charles Abbott, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Manuals, The Use of Iowa Clays in Small-Scale Production of Ceramic Art by Paul E. Cox, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Manuals, Kansas Volcanic Ash Resources, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Manuals, An Elementary Survey of Ceramic Processes, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Manuals, Glaze Calculation by Steven A. Goldberg, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 28-29)
  - Manuals, Fabrication of Plexiglas, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - New Brunswick Drawing Course Graded Practice Books by H. H. Hagerman, M.A., undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - A New Method of Assisting the Invention in Drawing Original Compositions of Landscape by Alexander Cozens, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - "The Music of Poetry," by T. S. Eliot, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Published Essays by Others, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - University of the Arts Brochures and Programs, 1987-1995, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Art Museum and Gallery Brochures, 1990-1992, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Duplicates of Published Writings by Daley, 1991, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Directions for "The Hat Trick", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Art Postcards, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 39-42)
  - Train Postcards, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 43)
- Photographs, 1953-1992, undated; Series 11; Archival Resource Key; 5 Folders Box 15
  This series contains photographs of William Daley throughout his career. The majority of the photographs depict Daley teaching and interacting with his students. Also included are photographs of the artist with his family, and early portraits of Daley working in his studio. There are also photographs of artwork by others ranging from outdoor sculpture to student work, and one file for unidentified photographs. Note that photographs related to certain events or artists may also be found in series 3, 4, 5 and 8.
  - William Daley and Family, 1984-1990, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 44)
  - Daley at Work, 1955-1964, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 45)
  - Class Photographs, 1953, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 46)
  - Artwork by Others, 1971, 1989, 1992, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 47)
  - Unidentified, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 48)
- Financial Files, 1962-1997, undated; Series 12; Archival Resource Key; 4 Folders Box 16
  This series consists of various bills, receipts, and expense lists. Also found is a list of pot sales for 1988 and a cash book containing expense lists for projects William Daley completed during the mid-1960s.
  - Cash Book, 1962-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Bills and Receipts, 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Pot Sales, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 1970, 1986-1997, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Artwork, 1954-2003, undated; Series 13; Archival Resource Key; 3 Folders Boxes 15-16
  The series consists of drawings and sketches by William Daley, including one file of eight original sketches for unidentified projects. Also found are two oversize files of signed copies made in 2003 of drawings done throughout Daley's career. This includes drawing studies for projects, compositions based on ceramic works, such as "Body Pot Revisited," and miscellaneous drawings such as "John Pickett in Hospital - Stroke" and a 1964 self-portrait. Items are arranged chronologically within each file.
  - Drawings, 1954-2003, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 49-50)
  - Sketches, 1968-1972, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Unprocessed Addition, circa 1959-2016; Series 14; Archival Resource Key; 11.1 Linear feet
  - Unprocessed Papers, Archival Resource Key (Box 17)
  - Unprocessed Papers, Archival Resource Key (Box 18)
  - Unprocessed Papers, Archival Resource Key (Box 19)
  - Unprocessed Papers, Archival Resource Key (Box 20)
  - Unprocessed Papers, Archival Resource Key (Box 21)
  - Unprocessed Papers, Archival Resource Key (Box 22)
  - Unprocessed Papers, Archival Resource Key (Box 23)
  - Unprocessed Papers, Archival Resource Key (Box 24)
  - Unprocessed Papers, Archival Resource Key (Box 25)
  - Unprocessed Papers, Archival Resource Key (Box 26)
  - Unprocessed Papers, Archival Resource Key (Box 27)
  - Unprocessed Papers, Archival Resource Key (Oversize 28)